<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pastor - Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/pastor/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 01:53:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Advice to young pastors: Preach the Gospel</title>
		<link>/index.php/advice-to-young-pastors-preach-the-gospel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 17:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=3084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Apostle Paul said: &#8220;For when I preach the gospel, I cannot boast, since I am compelled to preach. Woe to me if I do not preach the gospel!&#8221; (1 Corinthians 9:16). The anchor of our preaching must be the Good News of Jesus. It is so easy to get drawn into social commentary or [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/advice-to-young-pastors-preach-the-gospel/">Advice to young pastors: Preach the Gospel</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft " src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/notredame.jpg" width="471" height="353" />The Apostle Paul said: <em>&#8220;For when I preach the gospel, I cannot boast, since I am compelled to preach. Woe to me if I do not preach the gospel!&#8221;</em> (1 Corinthians 9:16). The anchor of our preaching must be the Good News of Jesus. It is so easy to get drawn into social commentary or political concerns or something similar. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, there&#8217;s a time and place to address current issues. However, they must always be addressed in the context of the Gospel message. &#8220;Our nation believes thus-and-so but, in Christ, the Lord offers us a better way.&#8221; It is so easy for the preacher to use pulpit time to denounce everything that is wrong while neglecting the hope that Jesus brings to the world. In the 1 Corinthians passage Paul is challenging the church&#8217;s treatment of himself. They have taken him for granted and even accused him of trying to boss them around. Paul defends himself, but also states, <em>&#8220;we put up with anything rather than hinder the gospel of Christ.&#8221;</em> For him, it is all about getting the Good News out. Pastor don&#8217;t squander your pulpit time on other stuff. When you do point out sin in society do so only to offer hope for the sinner. Our calling is clear: preach the Gospel.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/notredame.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-1835" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/notredame.jpg" alt="" width="1" height="1" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/advice-to-young-pastors-preach-the-gospel/">Advice to young pastors: Preach the Gospel</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Good Friday is a &#8220;No Parking Zone&#8221;</title>
		<link>/index.php/good-friday-is-a-no-parking-zone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 20:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The story of the Crucifixion is powerful. The cross was more an instrument of torture than it was one of execution. Some film makers have made it their mission to portray the agony of the cross with as much graphic realism possible.  Maybe it&#8217;s that realism or something else but it seems to me that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/good-friday-is-a-no-parking-zone/">Good Friday is a “No Parking Zone”</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/parking.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2545" src="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/parking.jpg" alt="parking" width="225" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/parking.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/04/parking-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></em>The story of the Crucifixion is powerful. The cross was more an instrument of torture than it was one of execution. Some film makers have made it their mission to portray the agony of the cross with as much graphic realism possible.  Maybe it&#8217;s that realism or something else but it seems to me that many Christians are stalled at the cross, thinking it is what Easter is all about.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not. Easter is about victory, hope, and redemption. The only reason to go to Good Friday is because we can&#8217;t get to Easter without it. However, the enduring symbol of Christianity isn&#8217;t (or at least shouldn&#8217;t be) a crucifix. Rather, it&#8217;s an empty cross. The reason we don&#8217;t make a cross with its victim our primary symbol isn&#8217;t because we can&#8217;t bear seeing Jesus hanging on it. We make an empty cross our primary symbol because Jesus is no longer on the cross. He has defeated it and all it stood for.</p>
<p>So, for believers, Good Friday is a &#8220;No Parking Zone.&#8221; We spend time on Good Friday remembering the cross and especially the love of Jesus for us that caused him to endure it. But we happily turn the page to Sunday morning, Resurrection Day.</p>
<p>Easter services shouldn&#8217;t be about the Crucifixion. References to the cross should be about Christ&#8217;s victory over it. If pastors and other church leaders have done their job the ordeal of the cross should have already been brought to the attention of the Church. That paves the way for Easter.  Individuals too should make it their practice to visit the cross on a regular basis, but not park there.  Its the Resurrection that transforms the crucifix into an empty cross and its the Resurrection that should be our primary focus.  Let&#8217;s turn the page from Good Friday and celebrate the Resurrection of our Lord and what it means to us.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/good-friday-is-a-no-parking-zone/">Good Friday is a “No Parking Zone”</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pastor, this is real commitment</title>
		<link>/index.php/pastor-this-is-real-commitment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I heard a pastor deliver a heartfelt message calling for his congregation to really commit to the church.  He told the church that he had had opportunities to go elsewhere, including a return to his home area to a previous pastorate.  However, he had turned it down because he was committed to this current church.  [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastor-this-is-real-commitment/">Pastor, this is real commitment</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-OIPxWg7XI4c/XBQDvFyKd8I/AAAAAAAA3-4/e6JgfdV0Bio3wJ-Nw4tC5c1p5-C0s3JQwCKgBGAs/s1600/photo.JPG" alt="" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oysterville Historic Church &#8211; Near Long Beach, WA (not the church in the story)</figcaption></figure>
<p>I heard a pastor deliver a heartfelt message calling for his congregation to really commit to the church.  He told the church that he had had opportunities to go elsewhere, including a return to his home area to a previous pastorate.  However, he had turned it down because he was committed to this current church.  Then, at the conclusion of the message all those in attendance were invited to join the pastor in his commitment by coming forward as a testimony to their allegiance.</p>
<p>Frankly, there was nothing wrong with any of this.  However, having known many of those laypersons for over 20 years I couldn&#8217;t help but smile to myself.  If anyone was qualified to call anyone to real commitment to the local church it was several of those laypersons.  They have already proven themselves faithful.  Several, for a lifetime.  They stayed true to that church through a series of pastors who after a while had declared that the Lord was calling them elsewhere.  They hung in there through some hard times when others moved on to a church down the street.</p>
<p>These were the people who had financially supported the church through the years.  They gave of their time by teaching Sunday School, working in VBS, leading Bible Quiz programs, and showing up for church work days.  They showed up for choir rehearsals and took a turn mowing the church lawn.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, pastors had come and gone.  Some retiring and others just packing up to continue their ministry elsewhere.  Listen, I know that that happens.  I do believe that there comes a time when a person needs to move on in their ministry – often for reasons they, themselves, don&#8217;t understand.  Circumstances change and both church and pastor can benefit from a healthy change.  Also, in my own ministry, especially in my younger years, I ran out of gas way too early in more than one assignment.  Happily, and to my credit (I think) my stays got longer as I matured in my ministry.</p>
<p>I also understand that some church people need to make a decision and quit playing church.  Some folks have been around the church for years and are still hanging out in the shallows rather than fully committing to the Lord and his Church.  They need to be challenged to go deeper in their spiritual lives.</p>
<p>Still, as I watched those who are prime examples of commitment and faithfulness respond to that sermon I couldn&#8217;t help but think things were the reverse of what they should have been.  It was those people who should have been challenging the pastor to commitment.  They should have been on the platform inviting him to come forward and accept their example.</p>
<p>Or, maybe said better, the good pastor should have told his congregation that the example of many in the congregation had inspired him and, as a result, he was committing to them to join them in their faithfulness.  I really doubt that some of them could be more committed to their church than they already are, and have proven over the decades.</p>
<p>Many churches are full of dedicated people who love their church and continue to sacrifice time, talent, and treasure.  We can only hope for pastors who will join them in that commitment.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastor-this-is-real-commitment/">Pastor, this is real commitment</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking for a pastor</title>
		<link>/index.php/looking-for-a-pastor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 22:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church of the Nazarene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nazarenes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My mother was a regular delegate to District Assembly (it&#8217;s a Nazarene thing). In the old days, every pastor on the district was required to give a verbal report to the Assembly. Some of the reports were inspiring and some not so much. At some point through the years Mom started &#8220;grading&#8221; pastors. If she [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/looking-for-a-pastor/">Looking for a pastor</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/checkmark.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-2763 size-thumbnail" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/checkmark-149x150.png" alt="" width="149" height="150" /></a>My mother was a regular delegate to District Assembly (it&#8217;s a Nazarene thing). In the old days, every pastor on the district was required to give a verbal report to the Assembly. Some of the reports were inspiring and some not so much. At some point through the years Mom started &#8220;grading&#8221; pastors. If she liked the way the pastor reported she would put a mark beside their name. She explained that if it so happened that during the year our church went through a pastoral transition (and it happened a lot during those days &#8211; the average pastoral tenure at that time was less than three years) she would use her star system to vet potential candidates.</p>
<p>Honestly, I don&#8217;t know that it ever happened that way, but she was ready &#8211; just in case.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/facebook-mobile-app-820x4201.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-2761 size-thumbnail" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/facebook-mobile-app-820x4201-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>As I remember her approach I realize that we do something similar with Facebook these days. In the past few years I&#8217;ve been involved in a couple of churches going through a change of pastors. Both times, as soon a potential candidate&#8217;s name became known a significant number of people headed for Facebook to find out all they could about the candidate.</p>
<p>And, using Facebook in particular and Google in general, you can find out a lot about a person. Some things are really easy to see and others take a bit of digging, but if a person is even marginally Facebook savvy they can learn a lot about someone who posts on Facebook.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not discounting the spiritual in the least here. For years I&#8217;ve encouraged church people to see a pastoral search as a spiritual rather than business endeavour. Still, I think church people are probably wise to use this to their advantage, at least in the early part of the process. We all know that resumes don&#8217;t tell the whole story. If a pastor is active on Facebook it is easy to get a more candid look at how they interact with people and what interests them when they are &#8220;off the clock.&#8221; This, I think, can help churches find a good match when they are looking for a new pastor.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/looking-for-a-pastor/">Looking for a pastor</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pastor Appreciation &#8211; why some churches don&#8217;t do it</title>
		<link>/index.php/pastor-appreciation-why-some-churches-dont-do-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 17:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor appreciation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking about why churches fail to honor their pastor during pastor appreciation month. I can think these possibilities:   1. In denominational churches at least, the district, etc. needs to contact church board secretaries prior to October, possibly with examples and suggestions, encouraging them to see to it that the pastor is honored. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastor-appreciation-why-some-churches-dont-do-it/">Pastor Appreciation – why some churches don’t do it</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="8k1fm-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="8k1fm-0-0"><span data-offset-key="8k1fm-0-0"><a href="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/thumbsup.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2656" src="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/thumbsup-163x300.png" alt="" width="163" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/thumbsup-163x300.png 163w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/thumbsup.png 391w" sizes="(max-width: 163px) 100vw, 163px" /></a>I&#8217;ve been thinking about why churches fail to honor their pastor during pastor appreciation month. I can think these possibilities:</span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="2om21-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="2om21-0-0"><span data-offset-key="2om21-0-0"> </span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="f5v78-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="f5v78-0-0"><span data-offset-key="f5v78-0-0">1. In denominational churches at least, <strong>the district, etc. needs to contact church board secretaries</strong> prior to October, possibly with examples and suggestions, encouraging them to see to it that the pastor is honored. Then in November, they should be contacted again, asking them what their church did.  If the church leadership isn&#8217;t being encouraged to honor their pastor by someone with authority, it may never happen.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="1f2q5-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="1f2q5-0-0"><span data-offset-key="1f2q5-0-0"> </span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="7ncnn-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="7ncnn-0-0"><span data-offset-key="7ncnn-0-0">2. I have the idea that<strong> church leaders who listen to Christian radio</strong> are more likely to honor their pastor during this time. Most Christian radio stations make a big deal out of it. If church leaders don&#8217;t listen to these stations (and I&#8217;m not saying they should), they won&#8217;t be influenced to take action.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="f5iov-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="f5iov-0-0"><span data-offset-key="f5iov-0-0"> </span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="9s8j4-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="9s8j4-0-0"><span data-offset-key="9s8j4-0-0">3.<strong> Many churches are so pastor-centric that nothing much happens unless the pastor is either leading it or at least approving it.</strong> (I had a women&#8217;s council one time that was amazed that I didn&#8217;t attend their meetings &#8211; all previous pastors had attended.) In the case of pastor appreciation, it doesn&#8217;t happen because the pastor isn&#8217;t in a position to organize it like he/she organizes everything else.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="boqtd-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="boqtd-0-0"><span data-offset-key="boqtd-0-0"> </span></div>
</div>
<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="8heli" data-offset-key="dui00-0-0">
<div class="_1mf _1mj" data-offset-key="dui00-0-0"><span data-offset-key="dui00-0-0">Just some passing late October thoughts.</span></div>
</div><p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastor-appreciation-why-some-churches-dont-do-it/">Pastor Appreciation – why some churches don’t do it</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pastors need Mondays</title>
		<link>/index.php/pastors-need-mondays/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 18:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabbatical leave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For many years prior to retirement from pastoring I took Mondays off. I generally took a long walk, did some banking, and pretty much crashed. Since retirement, of course, most days are “days off” so Mondays are pretty much like any other day of the week. Right now, I’m filling in for a friend who [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastors-need-mondays/">Pastors need Mondays</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft " src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IdWUlqxdQRA/Wy8JjHnFjDI/AAAAAAAAzDQ/2v6UdxPiU3ck_E1C5OY32beH1edYXc49QCKgBGAs/s1600/2013-07-04%2B12.11.39.jpg" width="297" height="223" />For many years prior to retirement from pastoring I took Mondays off. I generally took a long walk, did some banking, and pretty much crashed. Since retirement, of course, most days are “days off” so Mondays are pretty much like any other day of the week.</p>
<p>Right now, I’m filling in for a friend who is taking Sabbatical leave so I’m back “on the clock” at least in part. My only real responsibility is preaching the Sunday morning sermon although I’m “being the pastor” in a few other ways as well. I certainly don’t have the full pastoral load.</p>
<p>The interesting thing to me is that that old Monday weariness has returned. It has to be the preaching and maybe interacting with a number of people throughout the day because I’m not doing much else. I confess that I’m not much of a people person, so spending a large part of the day chatting and “being nice” does wear me down a bit. Still, I think the preaching is the biggest part of it.</p>
<p>It’s not as though I’m a high energy, pacing, pulpit pounder. My style is conversational, considerably thought through, and much prayed over. To most non-preachers I know that that doesn’t sound like much and some may accuse me of whining or maybe just of getting old and more easily tired. Honestly, there may be some truth in the second accusation and hopefully none in the first.</p>
<p>However, I think that there’s a least a reminder here that pastors work harder on Sundays than most people think they do, even if all they “do” is preach a sermon for 30-40 minutes. The preparation, both academic and spiritual, takes a toll. The energy spent, even with Spirit anointing, is considerable.</p>
<p>I don’t think I’m just whining or wimping out. Pastors carry a burden that takes a toll and they both need and deserve a Monday day of rest.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/pastors-need-mondays/">Pastors need Mondays</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Preaching for decisions: know when to land the sermon</title>
		<link>/index.php/preaching-for-decisions-know-when-to-land-the-sermon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 17:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I heard a well-prepared, well-delivered sermon that was intended to conclude with an invitation. As the sermon was finished a sweet spirit was evident in the service and I fully expected to see several people respond. The case had been made and the Spirit of the Lord was at work. But the preacher wouldn&#8217;t land the sermon! [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/preaching-for-decisions-know-when-to-land-the-sermon/">Preaching for decisions: know when to land the sermon</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/landing.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2615" src="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/landing-300x213.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="213" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/landing-300x213.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/landing.jpeg 320w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>I heard a well-prepared, well-delivered sermon that was intended to conclude with an invitation. As the sermon was finished a sweet spirit was evident in the service and I fully expected to see several people respond. The case had been made and the Spirit of the Lord was at work.</p>
<p>But the preacher wouldn&#8217;t land the sermon! Instead, we heard one more story followed by yet another application. By the time people were actually given opportunity to respond the moment had faded and the response was meager.</p>
<p>There are two points in the sermon that especially need to be well thought through by the preacher. The first is the first part of the sermon. The other is the closing of the sermon.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not saying that sermons should never include &#8220;in flight&#8221; direction of the Holy Spirit, even at crucial points (like leading to a call for decisions). However, the preacher needs to be careful to leave the Spirit room to work in the hearts of the listeners and be leery of telling &#8220;one more story.&#8221;</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/preaching-for-decisions-know-when-to-land-the-sermon/">Preaching for decisions: know when to land the sermon</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The biggest single change for pastors</title>
		<link>/index.php/the-biggest-single-change-for-pastors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 21:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was just thinking about the biggest single change I&#8217;ve seen in my 45 years of ministry. One big one was the move away from the KJV to the NIV (or some other modern version) being the most commonly used version of the Bible in our services by preachers. That changed sermons from being, to a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/the-biggest-single-change-for-pastors/">The biggest single change for pastors</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2592" src="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching-300x126.png" alt="preaching" width="500" height="210" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching-300x126.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching-768x323.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching-800x336.png 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/09/preaching.png 850w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p>I was just thinking about the biggest single change I&#8217;ve seen in my 45 years of ministry.</p>
<p><strong>One big one was the move away from the KJV to the NIV</strong> (or some other modern version) being the most commonly used version of the Bible in our services by preachers. That changed sermons from being, to a large part, translating Shakespearean language to modern English for our listeners to being more focused on the meaning of the text itself.</p>
<p><strong>Another big change was the addition of video to preaching</strong>. I know some pastors have yet to move toward it, but the vast majority of our churches have video up at least for scriptures, but often preaching is supplemented by professionally produced videos and clips from popular culture.</p>
<p><strong>A more subtle change is that our listeners now consume a wide variety of teaching</strong> ranging from TV and radio preachers to reading books or listening to podcasts from a variety of theological perspectives. This is a major change from the day when the local pastor was the primary source of teaching to those in the congregation. I&#8217;ve heard fine lay people repeat stuff that it is clearly incompatible with our doctrines. They&#8217;d heard it somewhere, and just accepted it because the speaker is a well known, capable teacher.</p>
<p><strong>I think, though, that the biggest change is the move away from Sunday night services.</strong></p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve just been saying, the pastor&#8217;s voice is diminished in the lives of church attenders already. So, while people are consuming a variety of religious teaching through the week, most pastors only address their congregations on Sunday mornings during the sermon. That limits the pastor&#8217;s influence over the congregation.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not saying, though, that this change is necessarily a bad thing. It was late in my active ministry that our church yielded to the reality that most people simply didn&#8217;t want to attend a Sunday night service. And it was only with that change in the church schedule that I had a taste of Sunday being a Christian Sabbath. For many years of my ministry I came to Sunday night exhausted. The concept that the pastor should take a different day as a day of rest never really worked for me. My weekly &#8220;day off&#8221; was filled with the kinds of things that most everyone does on their days off and not especially restful. I came to greatly appreciate Sunday afternoons as a time to unwind without needing to &#8220;reload&#8221; for the Sunday evening service.</p>
<p>Beyond that, being able to focus on Sunday morning only made me, I think, a better preacher. All my preparation time was toward one sermon. For non-preachers this may not sound like much but I think most preachers who read this will agree that focusing on one sermon a week makes a huge difference in preaching.</p>
<p>Of all the changes I&#8217;ve seen, I think the elimination of Sunday night church is the biggest.</p>
<p>What do you think?</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/the-biggest-single-change-for-pastors/">The biggest single change for pastors</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Advise to young pastors: Baptism</title>
		<link>/index.php/advise-to-young-pastors-baptism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 19:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church of the Nazarene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacraments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coming from a low church background I had very little pastoral training for conducting baptisms.  Also, in spite of my denomination&#8217;s acceptance of infant baptism, it was never practiced in the portions of the country where I grew up or ministered &#8211; everywhere I served people wanted to get wet all over and that&#8217;s what [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/advise-to-young-pastors-baptism/">Advise to young pastors: Baptism</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjLurhOhF9DR6R5LNQ5Zqn5cIgaXSO6kVFj52MdLMJAoGa_dfxfmdf0kngPtt97Gy3aOgLvbEBC0kiTnhN1jqjlSNUO1Rdq4ossiNNCIYfO8w8DwT385qqpKTbpvGweMsZ75ZfuBiNbk76b-kabzZmJs4__xqOVYvL-bmxyxAuQxYfOQzz7XgIXmOMbsEA9/s4032/20230424_114815.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" /></p>
<p>Coming from a low church background I had very little pastoral training for conducting baptisms.  Also, in spite of my denomination&#8217;s acceptance of infant baptism, it was never practiced in the portions of the country where I grew up or ministered &#8211; everywhere I served people wanted to get wet all over and that&#8217;s what happened.  Because of that, I&#8217;ll focus in on baptism services for youth and adults &#8211; and, for the sake of this article, I&#8217;m more thinking of in-church baptisms rather than I am those that take place at a lake or river (although most of my suggestions work either way).</p>
<ul style="list-style-type: circle;">
<li>Be sure people are prepared for baptism.  Pastor, that&#8217;s your job.  Don&#8217;t leave it to the youth pastor or Sunday School teacher or a parent.  Be ready to sit down with a candidate and, in an age appropriate way, work through what it means to be a Christian and why we baptize.  Of course, that means you have to understand it.  In our tradition we baptize as a means of grace.  That means, to us, it&#8217;s more than an outward witness.  It&#8217;s a sacrament &#8211; can you explain what that means to a 12 year old?  That&#8217;s exactly what you have to do if you are going to officiate at their baptism.</li>
<li>Write your own version of the baptism ritual.  I don&#8217;t mean that you have the freedom to make it say something it doesn&#8217;t already say, but if your candidates&#8217; (and your congregations&#8217;) eyes glaze over as you read the ritual you are just saying meaningless words.  Say it in such a way that they will understand what you are saying to them.</li>
<li>Have the candidates write out (or video) their testimony and have it read by a spiritual mentor just prior to their baptism.</li>
<li>Have everyone say the Apostle&#8217;s Creed together.  Don&#8217;t read the creed to the candidates &#8211; have them and the congregation say it and affirm it together.  After all, you are, by baptizing the candidates, uniting them with the congregation at a whole new level.  By the way, you and your congregation ought to be familiar with the Creed&#8230;maybe not memorized, but used to saying it.  This is who we are and what we believe.  Work it into Communion services or just include it in a service once a month.</li>
<li>If you are using some kind of hybrid baptistery where people sit down, etc.  then practice!  Let them get into the baptistery when it is dry and see what you expect of them (and yourself).  This is a big deal!  We rehearse weddings, why shouldn&#8217;t we rehearse baptisms?</li>
<li>Be prepared to help people in and out of the baptistery &#8211; they are nervous and distracted, and then wet!  Have someone ready to lend them a hand and hand them a towel.</li>
<li>Depending on how your baptistery is set up, invite family and guests to come to the platform to serve as witnesses (and take photos).  Beyond that, if you can, have the children and teens of the congregation to come up front to see it all.</li>
<li>Have everyone ready to cheer after each one &#8211; this is a big deal and a time of celebration.  Don&#8217;t let people just sit there watching the candidates get wet.</li>
<li>Once in a while, maybe once a year, prior to the baptismal service, preach on baptism.  Tell the congregation why it is a means of grace &#8211; have some of the senior saints ready to share the story of their baptism.  Then, with everyone freshly reminded of how wonderful it is, bring the candidates up!  Wow &#8211; what a great time you will have!</li>
<li>Once you are finished with the baptisms, and depending on your setup, take a bowl of the water from the baptismal and walk through the congregation inviting people to touch the water and &#8220;remember your baptism.&#8221;  If your sanctuary is set up to allow it, you might even have all who will to come forward and touch the water in the baptismal.</li>
<li>Even as you conclude the service, announce that you are ready to meet with others who would like to prepare for baptism.  You might just end up keeping the water for use next Sunday!</li>
</ul>
<p>These are my thoughts&#8230;what are yours?</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/advise-to-young-pastors-baptism/">Advise to young pastors: Baptism</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reflections on the second anniversary of my retirement</title>
		<link>/index.php/reflections-on-the-second-anniversary-of-my-retirement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 22:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church of the Nazarene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nazarenes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retirement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wow, retirement anniversary number two.  It was the first Sunday of May, 2013 that we concluded our pastoral ministry and entered into retirement.  In our case, we retired to travel and the very next day we drove off with our RV, starting the next primary chapter of our lives. This last year has been terrific.  [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/reflections-on-the-second-anniversary-of-my-retirement/">Reflections on the second anniversary of my retirement</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjMuuizvxbryMKJDoT7OFMm5y1_5rFMVv8gReLwvv5ZtpAO77PaLyvoO569XSuDJHr_QDZJABbHs6OG1GXQLDGXD7ZxDBDNfHrZxIh4JtAcqEtaQzQUArCWApC5V_yFFxWNQSdtCJVhTO0ioJ705Czpwhe778K4G9kqDqb9BkHdacbs5vTNO6r7xrSCkww4/s4032/20230424_114824.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" /></p>
<p>Wow, retirement anniversary number two.  It was the first Sunday of May, 2013 that we concluded our pastoral ministry and entered into retirement.  In our case, we retired to travel and the very next day we drove off with our RV, starting the next primary chapter of our lives.</p>
<p>This last year has been terrific.  <a href="http://pastorscott.com/travel/2014-adventure-wrap-up/">We traveled from Houston to the northwestern corner </a>of the continental United States and then journeyed at a leisurely pace south along the western coast where we enjoyed amazing scenery and cool Pacific Ocean temperatures.  We visited numerous national parks and, in general, had a blast.</p>
<p>Our winter and early spring has been spent doing a variation of our fulltime RVing lifestyle.  We’ve <a href="http://pastorscott.com/travel/update-wrap-up-on-volunteering-at-san-jacinto-monumentbattleship-texas/">volunteered at the Texas San Jacinto Battleground/Battleship Texas State Historic Park</a>.  In exchange for donating 100 hours of our time each month we’ve enjoyed “free parking.”  That “trade” has saved us some serious, and needed, cash! We’ve thoroughly enjoyed this experience which allowed us to do some very interesting things while being close to family and friends.  While we’re more than ready to begin our travels again we enjoyed the volunteering experience enough that we’ve already signed up to do it again next year.</p>
<p>I did a few more clergy-like things than I did our first year but not a lot.  I filled for our pastor when he was away, filled in for our Sunday School teacher (who happens to be my son) when he was away, did a baby dedication, and finalized <a href="http://pastorscott.com/index.php/books-by-pastor-scott/">my series of books of devotionals</a>.  Aside from that I’ve happily sat in the pew, appreciating the ministry of others.</p>
<p>All in all, we’ve spent over 4 months in the Houston area during this stay.  That means we suspended our “<a href="http://pastorscott.com/travel/church-hopping-observations/">church hopping</a>” ways and settled into a more typical church attendance routine.  While visiting many different churches during our travels is enjoyable we’ve missed the sense of community associated with being a part of a congregation.  This being our second winter as part of our home church helped us feel more a part of things.  It’s interesting to me how things we at first felt were somehow different become, in just a few weeks, just “the way it is done here.”  One thing that become increasingly clear is that no church can be evaluated in just a week or two.  Churches have personalities and that personality isn’t apparent until one is part of the congregation (and involved beyond an hour on Sunday mornings) for a while.  Don’t get me wrong: I enjoy visiting churches, but I know that being a regular, contributing part of a church <span style="color: #444444;">family is superior.</span></p>
<p>So, I’d say retirement is going quite well, thank you!  We’re well aware that we are blessed to live this life and we don’t take it for granted.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/reflections-on-the-second-anniversary-of-my-retirement/">Reflections on the second anniversary of my retirement</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
