<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>time &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/time/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pastor&#8217;s day off and other pastor/time issues</title>
		<link>/index.php/pastors-day-off-and-other-pastortime-issues/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 17:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/?p=1620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have four things to say to pastors about &#8220;days off&#8221; and how, in general, a pastor spends his or her time. First, unless you ditch the cell phone and head for parts unknown there&#8217;s no literal day &#8220;off.&#8221; Rather, they&#8217;re just days &#8220;on call.&#8221; In this case, it&#8217;s no different for pastors than it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have four things to say to pastors about &#8220;days off&#8221; and how, in general, a pastor spends his or her time.</p>
<p>First, unless you ditch the cell phone and head for parts unknown  there&#8217;s no literal day &#8220;off.&#8221;  Rather, they&#8217;re just days &#8220;on call.&#8221;  In  this case, it&#8217;s no different for pastors than it is for many other  professionals and business people.  Rather, it&#8217;s just the way it is.</p>
<p>Second, you&#8217;re in this for the long haul.  The dedicated,  burning-the-candle-at-both-ends kind of pastor will get lots of applause  from some in the congregation and maybe will even be &#8220;honored&#8221; by being  asked to take on yet more responsibilities at the community, district,  or denominational level.  It&#8217;s important to remember that some of these  good people will applaud you right into the grave.  If your ministry is  going to last a lifetime, it needs to be run at a jog rather than at a  sprint.</p>
<p>Third, life is short and there&#8217;s no rewind button. Your kids (and then  grandkids) grow up quickly. Your relationship with your loved ones needs  attention.  Also, while a quiet lifestyle is practically unheard of  these days, for a person seeking God&#8217;s heart it&#8217;s vitally important.  A  less intense lifestyle may produce a spiritual depth that will flow in  natural ways into your ministry&#8230;accomplishing more genuine ministry to  others than a frantic run on some church schedule treadmill seven days a  week.</p>
<p>Fourth, beware of letting others set your schedule.  One group thinks  you need to attend every church event (years ago the ladies at the  womens meeting actually asked Jackie if I was coming &#8211; after all the  previous pastor had always stuck his head in the door for their meetings  &#8211; she laughed and said they had better not expect me).  A certain age  group would be happy if you took on the role specifically given to the  laypeople of the church and spent a lot of time ministering to the  &#8220;widows.&#8221;  Others will make you their father confessor and lock you into  a brutal counseling session schedule.  If you like that stuff, okay,  maybe.  However, the pastor needs to have a strong sense of self  identity and not let others control the schedule.  (By the way, I don&#8217;t  think the pastor should give a detailed time report to the board for  just that reason &#8211; you&#8217;ll never win because they all think they know  what you&#8217;re supposed to do with your time.)</p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve already mentioned, I don&#8217;t think the pastor&#8217;s situation is  greatly different than that of many other professionals and business  owners.  I guess a case could be made that since we&#8217;re dealing with  people at a spiritual level and since we believe eternity is, indeed,  forever, that there&#8217;s a bit more pressure, but I&#8217;m not sure that&#8217;s  actually in play at a practical level.</p>
<p>Take some time off&#8230;not just for vacation time, or even a day or two a  week &#8220;off,&#8221; but every day.  Don&#8217;t be ashamed or apologetic.  Go toss the  ball around with your kids.  You and your spouse go for a long  no-church-business-discussed walk.  Watch some TV or read a  nothing-to-do-with-church book. Sit around thinking about the things of  God, not for a sermon, but just so you&#8217;ll understand such things better.    In the long run, you&#8217;ll likely do more for the Kingdom that way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
