<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>liturgy - Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/liturgy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 01:38:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Confession of a non-liturgical pastor</title>
		<link>/index.php/confession-of-a-non-liturgical-pastor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 14:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liturgy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/?p=1784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Confession of a non-liturgical (at least in the strictest definition of the term) pastor&#8230; Several years ago as I read the history of Christianity I was taken with the emphasis on the public reading of Scripture &#8211; something specifically mentioned by Paul to Timothy. I decided that if it we&#8217;re specifically told to do so [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/index.php/confession-of-a-non-liturgical-pastor/">Confession of a non-liturgical pastor</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjiFaMj5-0lO7LSqebTJz9Q7VkKSpSWg95pMfgGqmj1gHPv3ixFs_SGxLPPuC_bNOxb6xj2jceY7Z89XDJ9deQwcV1KYbXlhMgxpdolwSF-HmyH303VGW1OFtFQS5QhlYrh-e6OlnQh7EB08PbsnsAszcl6T29HEL3i6Q0Nyepmzh_rSJJFbLSYjAai2jc5/s4032/20230429_141153.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" /></p>
<p>Confession of a non-liturgical (at least in the strictest definition of the term) pastor&#8230;</p>
<p>Several years ago as I read the history of Christianity I was taken with the emphasis on the public reading of Scripture &#8211; something specifically mentioned by Paul to Timothy.</p>
<p>I decided that if it we&#8217;re specifically told to do so in the Bible and since it was deeply rooted in the history of the Church that I&#8217;d add the reading of Scripture to the regular order of the service. (Note: &#8220;Order of worship&#8221; is how we non-liturgicals talk about liturgy.)</p>
<p>The question then became what passage to read. My first inclination was to use the passage I was going to preach from later in the service. That, though, had some limitations &#8212; really, not all preachable portions of Scripture lend themselves to the reading of Scripture in worship service.</p>
<p>Also, I was still challenged to lift the Scripture, itself. If I read my text early, I was really still reading it as part of the sermon. I wanted to let the Scripture, at that point, just speak for itself and be separate from the sermon.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I decided to go with at least a portion of the Gospel reading from the Book of Common Prayer. It gives us a bit of structure and a certain flow week by week. So each week a lay reader leads us in a responsive reading from the Gospels.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not preaching from it and I still don&#8217;t use the lectionary, although I&#8217;m not critical of those who do.</p>
<p>By the way, sometime later I added a weekly Psalm, which I use as a call to worship. Then, more recently, I&#8217;ve added the reading of one of the wonderful Biblical benedictions to each service.</p>
<p>A Biblical call to worship, a responsive reading from the Word, an expository sermon, and a benediction from Scripture&#8230;nope, I&#8217;m not liturgical, I just like to use the Bible in worship.</p><p>The post <a href="/index.php/confession-of-a-non-liturgical-pastor/">Confession of a non-liturgical pastor</a> first appeared on <a href="">Pastor Scott's Ministerially Speaking</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
