<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Second Coming &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/second-coming/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:53:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hurricanes and the Return of Christ</title>
		<link>/index.php/hurricanes-and-the-return-of-christ/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 03:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricane Rita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Coming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2006/03/12/hurricanes-and-the-return-of-christ/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Originally posted 9-23-05 We are ready to wait out hurricane Rita in an area that is expecting lots of rain and winds of 50 to 60 mph. Not the perfect place, but out of the worst of the storm. I got an email from a friend I haven&#8217;t heard from in a long time. He [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Originally posted 9-23-05</p>
<p>We are ready to wait out hurricane Rita in an area that is expecting lots of rain and winds of 50 to 60 mph.  Not the perfect place, but out of the worst of the storm.</p>
<p>I got an email from a friend I haven&#8217;t heard from in a long time.  He isn&#8217;t in the path of any storms but it was clear that he is upset and concerned in the face of so much unrest in the world.  Katrina, Rita, terrorism, the war in Iraq, rising fuel prices &#8212; these are days of uncertainty.  He wonders if this is the beginning of the end of the world.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t answer that question, although I do think that storms and such are just part of living in a world where bad things happen to even good people.  My best advice is to get ready and stay ready for the sure Return of Christ.  We don&#8217;t know &#8220;when&#8221; but we do know that it is a &#8220;sure thing&#8221; &#8212; Jesus is coming back and the world, we know it, is going to be totally changed.</p>
<p>However, there is even more here.  When we give our lives to Christ things are not the same afterward.  First, our relationship with God is changed &#8212; we have &#8220;made peace&#8221; with our Maker.  Second, we are changed.  God begins a process of transforming our lives.  The result of this is the possibility of our facing uncertainties with new eyes.  That is where the famous &#8220;peace that passes understanding&#8221; comes in.</p>
<p>One more thing though &#8212; the peace of Christ is not automatic, even for Christians.  We have to receive that peace.  If we don&#8217;t, we are in no better shape, peace-wise than anyone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
