<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>humor &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/humor/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:53:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Learning to laugh at yourself</title>
		<link>/index.php/learning-to-laugh-at-yourself/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 16:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blunders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/?p=1803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I know that preaching is serious business and I take it seriously. Still, there&#8217;s a place for humor &#8211; not as an add on that sticks out like a sore thumb, but as part of an illustration that helps drive home an important truth. Then, there&#8217;s the unintentional humor that happens at sometimes unwelcome times. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know that preaching is serious business and I take it seriously.  Still, there&#8217;s a place for humor &#8211; not as an add on that sticks out like a sore thumb, but as part of an illustration that helps drive home an important truth.</p>
<p>Then, there&#8217;s the unintentional humor that happens at sometimes unwelcome times.  Preachers are notorious for getting tongues tangled &#8212; for foot-in-mouth disease.  A friend of mine made a huge goof one time that had the congregation so ticked that he good-naturedly just closed the service!</p>
<p>I was once praying a sincere prayer and heard myself devoutly pray: &#8220;Oh, Lord, we come to you in true humidity.&#8221;  Along the Texas Gulf Coast that may be more true than what I intended to say in the first place.</p>
<p>Last Sunday as I preached a sermon on Lot&#8217;s wife, I commented that we don&#8217;t know the names of all the women in the Bible and we don&#8217;t know her&#8217;s.  Then, somewhere early in her story I said something like, &#8220;Lot&#8217;s wife husband,  Lot, decided to join his uncle in his journey.&#8221;  Even as I said it I  got tickled.  Yep, Lot&#8217;s wife&#8217;s husband was named Lot all right.  It  took me a minute or so to get my act back together.</p>
<p>Anyway, we don&#8217;t know Mrs. Lot&#8217;s name&#8230;but I&#8217;m quite sure that Lot&#8217;s wife&#8217;s husband was named Lot.</p>
<p>Sometimes, you just have to laugh at yourself, pick up the pieces, and move on the best you can.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Humor of Abraham Lincoln</title>
		<link>/index.php/humor-of-abraham-lincoln/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 02:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham Lincoln]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2006/03/12/humor-of-abraham-lincoln/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love this letter from Abraham Lincoln: One day . . . I got into a fit of musing in my room and stood resting my elbows on the bureau. Looking into the glass, it struck me what an ugly man I was. The fact grew on me and I made up my mind that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love this letter from Abraham Lincoln:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>One day . . . I got into a fit of musing in my room and stood resting my elbows on the bureau. Looking into the glass, it struck me what an ugly man I was. The fact grew on me and I made up my mind that I must be the ugliest man in the world. It so maddened me that I resolved, should I ever see an uglier, I would shoot him on sight. Not long after this, Andy [naming a lawyer present] came to town and the first time I saw him I said to myself: &#8216;There&#8217;s the man.&#8217; I went home, took down my gun, and prowled around the streets waiting for him. He soon came along. &#8216;Halt, Andy,&#8217; said I, pointing the gun at him, &#8216;say your prayers, for I am going to shoot you.&#8217; &#8216;Why, Mr. Lincoln, what&#8217;s the matter? What have I done?&#8217; &#8216;Well, I made an oath that if I ever saw an uglier man than I am, I&#8217;d shoot him on the spot. You are uglier, surely; so make ready to die.&#8217; &#8216;Mr. Lincoln, do you really think that I am uglier than you?&#8217; &#8216;Yes.&#8217; &#8216;Well, Mr. Lincoln,&#8217; said Andy deliberately and looking me squarely in the face, &#8216;if I am any uglier, fire away.&#8217; </em></p></blockquote>
<p>There are several other funny letters from famous people at:<br />
<a href="http://www.wnyc.org/books/15539">www.wnyc.org/books/15539</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
