<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sabbatical leave &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sabbatical-leave/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:53:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pastors need Mondays</title>
		<link>/index.php/pastors-need-mondays/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 18:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabbatical leave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For many years prior to retirement from pastoring I took Mondays off. I generally took a long walk, did some banking, and pretty much crashed. Since retirement, of course, most days are “days off” so Mondays are pretty much like any other day of the week. Right now, I’m filling in for a friend who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft " src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IdWUlqxdQRA/Wy8JjHnFjDI/AAAAAAAAzDQ/2v6UdxPiU3ck_E1C5OY32beH1edYXc49QCKgBGAs/s1600/2013-07-04%2B12.11.39.jpg" width="297" height="223" />For many years prior to retirement from pastoring I took Mondays off. I generally took a long walk, did some banking, and pretty much crashed. Since retirement, of course, most days are “days off” so Mondays are pretty much like any other day of the week.</p>
<p>Right now, I’m filling in for a friend who is taking Sabbatical leave so I’m back “on the clock” at least in part. My only real responsibility is preaching the Sunday morning sermon although I’m “being the pastor” in a few other ways as well. I certainly don’t have the full pastoral load.</p>
<p>The interesting thing to me is that that old Monday weariness has returned. It has to be the preaching and maybe interacting with a number of people throughout the day because I’m not doing much else. I confess that I’m not much of a people person, so spending a large part of the day chatting and “being nice” does wear me down a bit. Still, I think the preaching is the biggest part of it.</p>
<p>It’s not as though I’m a high energy, pacing, pulpit pounder. My style is conversational, considerably thought through, and much prayed over. To most non-preachers I know that that doesn’t sound like much and some may accuse me of whining or maybe just of getting old and more easily tired. Honestly, there may be some truth in the second accusation and hopefully none in the first.</p>
<p>However, I think that there’s a least a reminder here that pastors work harder on Sundays than most people think they do, even if all they “do” is preach a sermon for 30-40 minutes. The preparation, both academic and spiritual, takes a toll. The energy spent, even with Spirit anointing, is considerable.</p>
<p>I don’t think I’m just whining or wimping out. Pastors carry a burden that takes a toll and they both need and deserve a Monday day of rest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Preparing the church for a pastoral sabbatical</title>
		<link>/index.php/preparing-the-church-for-a-pastoral-sabbatical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 21:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabbatical leave]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The value of a pastor taking a sabbatical leave after a number of years of service to a local congregation is gaining more and more recognition.  In this post I’m not going to attempt to make a case for sabbatical leave, but am going to talk about how a church can prepare for the pastor’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The value of a pastor taking a sabbatical leave after a number of years of service to a local congregation is gaining more and more recognition.  In this post I’m not going to attempt to make a case for sabbatical leave, but am going to talk about how a church can prepare for the pastor’s absence for an extended amount of time.  This subject needs careful consideration and it’s important for the pastor as well as for the congregation.  Outsiders might think that all the pastor does is preach a sermon every Sunday morning, but as they say, that’s just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>Generally speaking, the pastor not only does “spiritual things” like making hospital visits and carrying a burden of prayer for the church family but also functions as a sort of CEO who makes constant on-the-fly decisions concerning how the church calendar is organized, what is emphasized in the church announcements, and what “extra” features are included in a given Sunday’s order of worship.</p>
<p>If the pastor just walks away, off to enjoy a month’s long sabbatical a power void will be created in the church.  Well-meaning people will sense that void and step into fill it and some, who maybe aren’t so well-meaning will see it as an opportunity to reshape the church as they see fit.  The pastor who has happily ridden off into the sunset may return to find such a mess that all the relaxation of the sabbatical will drain away as they have to deal with the destruction that the power void has created.</p>
<p>With all that in mind, a wise pastor and church leadership will firmly address leadership issues before the pastor leaves town.  Here are some suggestions:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Don’t just engage a sabbatical interim pastor</strong> and toss it all in their lap.  There are levels of trust and responsibility that an outsider, or even an insider lacking sufficient experience, can’t address.  Make a list of exactly what that person will do: preaching, administering the sacraments, praying the pastoral prayer.  The interim will basically do the “tip of the iceberg” stuff that outsiders think is the only thing the pastor does.</li>
<li><strong>List all the other things the pastor normally does</strong> in a week and assign each portion of that to a different lay leader.  Who will initiate the church prayer chain?  Who will visit the sick in the hospital?   Fill every position with a willing layperson.</li>
<li><strong>List all the organizational responsibilities of the pastor</strong> and assign them.  Different churches have different organizational flows, but if the pastor signs off on the music, what goes into the church bulletin, etc. name the person who is going to have that authority.</li>
<li><strong>Name a person who will serve as “service platform manager”</strong> – they will do the things in the service that the pastor normally does: do the call to worship, offer the benediction, call for the ushers, welcome visitors, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Commit to the current structure of the church</strong> during the sabbatical.  There will be no changes to the order of worship, the makeup of the praise team, or the leadership of the church.  The sabbatical will not be the time when things will be changed because someone with a big voice insists that the offering should be taken differently or the announcements should be done at a different time in the service.</li>
<li>Having prepared for all the expected things, prepare for the unexpected.  <strong>Create a “pastoral committee”</strong> of three trusted lay leaders in the church.  Grant them “pastoral authority” in the church.  When a decision has to be made that would normally be made by the pastor, refer it to the committee – any two of the three can decide.  Some churches think that they will just give the interim pastor that authority, but that’s a mistake.  That person won’t have the knowledge of people and past practices of the church to make decisions as the pastor.  If the church names just one lay person their decisions will be subject to doubt and disagreement.  A committee of three will carry a sense of authority and fairness.</li>
</ol>
<p>All of the above can be done in just one board meeting if the pastor has done the necessary homework to list all that they do in a given week.  Having made the appointments, publish them in the church bulletin prior to and then during the duration of the sabbatical.  It will remind the congregation that the church isn’t adrift while the pastor is away.  It will remind those who have an agenda of their own that there is already an agenda in place.  Not only that, but developing lay leaders is a Biblical model for the church.  The returning pastor might just find that some of the things that have been occupying his or her time really was never his or her job in the first place!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plugged and unplugged</title>
		<link>/index.php/plugged-and-unplugged-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricane Ike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabbatical leave]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2009/10/01/plugged-and-unplugged-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A friend of ours, I&#8217;ll call her &#8220;TB,&#8221; looked over my Miscellaneous writing and found that I have been rather inconsistent in my observations.  Following Hurricane Ike I waxed eloquent about our twelve days without electricity.  However, looking a bit farther back in my ramblings, she found my sanguine thoughts on camping unplugged and how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A friend of ours, I&#8217;ll call her &#8220;TB,&#8221; looked over my Miscellaneous writing and found that I have been rather inconsistent in my observations.  Following Hurricane Ike I <a href="http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2008/09/23/hurricane-ike-20-give-me-power/">waxed eloquent</a> about our twelve days without electricity.  However, looking a bit farther back in my ramblings, she found my sanguine thoughts on <a href="http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2008/05/20/sabbatical-journey-12/">camping unplugged</a> and how peaceful it is.  What can I say?  Sitting beside a beautiful mountain stream with nothing more important to do than start the campfire for the evening is more fun than sitting in the garage hoping for a whisper of a breeze on a hot September Texas Gulf Coast day!</p>
<p>Still, I get the point.  A lot of things just depend on our perspective.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
