<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>children &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Ministerially Speaking</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/children/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Random Observations from Pastor Scott Cundiff</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 20:06:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Advice to young pastors: Minister to Children</title>
		<link>/index.php/minister-to-children/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=3306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Matthew 19:14 Jesus says: “Let the little children come to me, and do not hinder them, for the kingdom of heaven belongs to such as these.” I understand that it is common for people of that society to bring their children to respected rabbis to receive a blessing. People who see Jesus as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/girl.png"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3505" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/girl.png" alt="" width="168" height="227" /></a>In Matthew 19:14 Jesus says: <em>“Let the little children come to me, and do not hinder them, for the kingdom of heaven belongs to such as these.”</em> I understand that it is common for people of that society to bring their children to respected rabbis to receive a blessing. People who see Jesus as a worthy teacher want him to bless their children but for some reason the disciples don&#8217;t want them to interrupt the &#8220;important&#8221; work Jesus is doing to stop and deal with children.</p>
<p>Jesus famously welcomes the children and uses them to reenforce his teaching on how to live in the Kingdom of God.</p>
<p>One way the Church tries to follow this &#8220;let the little children come&#8221; directive of our Lord is by practicing child baptism, or baby dedication. Churches often make a serious effort to minister to children by staffing a children&#8217;s department in the church program.</p>
<p>While I appreciate the need for children&#8217;s programming in the church, I think we need to be careful to involve them in the larger life of the church. It is worth the effort to find ways to connect our boys and girls to the worship services. While I don&#8217;t think we need to turn Sunday morning worship into a big &#8220;children&#8217;s church&#8221; I do think we can make an effort to include children in our regular worship services, if not every Sunday, at least on a regular basis. Children should be familiar with what we do in church even when the service isn&#8217;t all about them (in a Christmas program, for instance).</p>
<p>Pastors should be able to craft sermons that are easy for elementary children to follow. If needed, most children&#8217;s workers can suggest handouts, crafts, visual aids to help children connect to a well-planned sermon meant to minister to both children and adults. Also, it is likely a good thing for the pastor to practice a bit of self-discipline in regard to sermon length and material.  Granted, I&#8217;m not thinking so much of an every-Sunday approach here (although some carry it off nicely) as I am of maybe a monthly &#8220;family Sunday&#8221; or something similar.</p>
<p>Really, Jesus didn&#8217;t tell the disciples to take the children off to another room and teach them a children&#8217;s lesson. Rather, he included them in what he was doing right then and there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Communion</title>
		<link>/index.php/communion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 22:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church of the Nazarene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lord's Supper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nazarenes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacraments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/speaking/?p=2257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I grew up in a very “low church” worship environment.  Our Nazarene Manual directed us to receive the Lord’s Supper at least once a quarter and, apparently, we saw that as a maximum rather than minimum frequency.   As a young pastor I followed that same schedule but over time I moved to a monthly observance, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2261" alt="communion" src="http://localhost/speaking/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion-800x533.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/communion-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>I grew up in a very “low church” worship environment.  Our Nazarene Manual directed us to receive the Lord’s Supper at least once a quarter and, apparently, we saw that as a maximum rather than minimum frequency.   As a young pastor I followed that same schedule but over time I moved to a monthly observance, trying to find a middle way between seeing the sacrament as the featured act of worship at one extreme, and as a mandated add-on at the other extreme.</p>
<p>While I don’t think there is a right or wrong approach in how most churches observe the sacrament I do think that the freedom to vary the emphasis and approach and even mechanics of observing it can be an advantage for less liturgical churches.   Whether or not you agree with me here, I hope you’ll find some of these thoughts helpful.</p>
<p><b>Communion is more of a celebration than anything else.</b>  We don’t believe Jesus dies again each time we receive communion and it isn’t only about shed blood and broken body.   Mainly, we’re celebrating the amazing love the Lord has for us.   Jesus willingly went to the cross because “God so loved the world.”  There, on that old rugged cross, he conquered sin and death.  His victory has become mine.  We don’t celebrate the brokenness and bleeding but we do celebrate the reason for it and what it has accomplished in and for us. <i> “We come today to celebrate the greatest act of love, the most beneficial sacrifice ever accomplished….”</i></p>
<p><b>Communion is the perfect platform for inviting people to come to Jesus. </b> As a young person I somehow had the idea that the Lord’s Supper could be hazardous to one’s health.  We were to examine ourselves and if we had experienced any spiritual failure we might be wise to skip communion that quarter.  Over time I began to understand that, while it was possible to receive communion in an unworthy manner (that is, without showing proper reverence) that, honestly, no one is worthy of receiving these emblems of the Lord’s body and blood.  Had we been worthy, he would have never had to go to the cross in the first place.  With that in mind, I began to see the sacrament as an invitation to Christ.  As I examine my heart and realize that there are spiritual failures I’m not disqualified from the bread and wine.  Rather, I’m being given an opportunity to avail myself of the mercy and grace of the Lord in a fresh way.  If I come, viewing my receiving communion as a substitute for repentance and faith I’m moving into the “unworthy” territory.  If I come seeking forgiveness and restoration, though, I find life in that sacrament.  <i>“The Bible says we’re to examine ourselves before receiving communion.  So let’s do that.  If, as you consider your relationship with the Lord and find that things aren’t what they ought to be, that doesn’t mean you can’t receive communion today.  Instead, this is an opportunity to make things right with the Lord.  As you receive the bread and wine, receive Jesus into your life all over again.”</i></p>
<p><b>Communion is a great way to introduce your child to Jesus.</b>  Honestly, I think our liturgical friends with their emphasis on “first communion” have a great approach.  However, that doesn’t mean that there aren’t advantages to a less structured, low church approach.  As a pastor I allowed parents to bring their children forward to receive communion provided the parent agreed to have a discussion with that child about allowing Jesus to be their Lord and Savior before the day was over.  Symbols are powerful and children can grasp spiritual realities earlier than we might think.  I let parents decide if their children are “there” yet.  <i>“Parents, I’ll let you decide when your children are ready to receive communion.  If you do allow your child to come today, I ask this of you: let’s agree that before this day is over you will sit down with your child and talk about the meaning of communion and how it is that a person places their faith in Jesus.”</i></p>
<p><b>Communion ought to be the focus of at least one service a year.</b>  Baptism has been called the “entry sacrament” to our life in Christ.  Communion is the “continuing sacrament.”  One Sunday a year the church service should be all about the Lord’s Supper (World Communion Sunday is the first Sunday of October).   Sing songs about it, read the appropriate scriptures, and preach a sermon that reminds us why we celebrate communion.  Talk about our unity with believers across the ages and in the various traditions of Christianity.  Talk about God’s love for us and Christ’s willingness to die for us.  Remind people of its connection to the Marriage Supper of the Lamb.  Tell them why the Lord’s Supper is called a “means of grace.”  Then, invite people to the table of the Lord.  Pastor, on this Sunday, you do all the serving, taking the role of Jesus, himself.  <i>“Today is World Communion Sunday and we’re going to join Christians of many traditions around the world in receiving communion.  Before we do that though, let’s think about the meaning and purpose of this sacrament of the Church.”</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If you have a child who is away from God today&#8230;</title>
		<link>/index.php/if-you-have-a-child-who-is-away-from-god-today/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ministerially_speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresh Wind Fresh Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Cymbala]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/miscellany/2006/03/12/if-you-have-a-child-who-is-away-from-god-today/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am re-reading Jim Cymbala&#8217;s &#8220;Fresh Wind Fresh Fire&#8221; and just finished the chapter in which he talks about his daughter who was living far from God. If you have a child who is away from God today I recommend that you get this book and read this chapter. The price of the book is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am re-reading Jim Cymbala&#8217;s &#8220;Fresh Wind Fresh Fire&#8221; and just finished the chapter in which he talks about his daughter who was living far from God.</p>
<p>If you have a child who is away from God today I recommend that you get this book and read this chapter.  The price of the book is worth it just for this story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
